<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>iPhone - Tag - kayak4665664&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/iphone/</link>
    <description>iPhone - Tag - kayak4665664&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 10:45:44 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/iphone/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
  <title>Use Phone Buddy on Apple Watch to Prevent Forgotten iPhone</title>
  <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/use-phone-buddy-on-apple-watch-to-prevent-forgotten-iphone/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 10:45:44 &#43;0800</pubDate>
  <author>kayak4665664</author>
  <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/use-phone-buddy-on-apple-watch-to-prevent-forgotten-iphone/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Today my dad drove me to a place. After I got off the car and walked for 3 minutes, I suddenly found that my mobile phone was missing&hellip;</p>
<p>I hurried back to the same place to look for my mobile phone, but I couldn&rsquo;t find it. Finally, I borrowed a mobile phone from the traffic police on the side of the road and called my father to confirm that my mobile phone was left in the car.</p>
<p>Although Find My has been set to send a notification on the Apple Watch when I leave my iPhone, it seems that this function needs to be at a relatively long distance to take effect.</p>
<p>So I found <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/phone-buddy-phone-lost-alert/id1451559391"target="_blank" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer">Phone Buddy<i class="fa-solid fa-external-link-alt fa-fw fa-xs ms-1 text-secondary" aria-hidden="true"></i></a>, the price is $4.99, I <a href="https://www.kayak4665664.com/buy-us-app-store-gift-cards-with-alipay/"target="_blank" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer">bought a US App Store Gift Card with Alipay<i class="fa-solid fa-external-link-alt fa-fw fa-xs ms-1 text-secondary" aria-hidden="true"></i></a> to recharge and purchase this App.</p>
<div class="details admonition note open">
    <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
      <i class="icon fa-solid fa-pencil-alt fa-fw" aria-hidden="true"></i>Note<i class="details-icon fa-solid fa-angle-right fa-fw" aria-hidden="true"></i>
    </div>
    <div class="details-content">
      <div class="admonition-content">After downloading Phone Buddy, turn on Lost Phone Alert on the Apple Watch, and when the Apple Watch loses the Bluetooth connection with the iPhone, an alert will be sent to the Apple Watch. And there can also be a Distance Alert. When the Bluetooth signal strength between the Apple Watch and iPhone decays below the set threshold with the increase of distance, an alert can also be issued, so that it can be one more time before the Bluetooth connection is completely disconnected. Similarly, you can also set an alert on the iPhone after the Apple Watch is disconnected, which can prevent the Apple Watch from being lost or forgotten.</div>
    </div>
  </div>
<p>The only downside is that this App will shorten the battery life of the Apple Watch, but compared to losing my iPhone, this price is acceptable.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
