<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>overseas payment - Tag - kayak4665664</title>
        <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/overseas-payment/</link>
        <description>overseas payment - Tag - kayak4665664</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 22:06:38 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/overseas-payment/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Depay: a Virtual US Dollar Credit Card for Spending With USDT</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/depay-a-virtual-dollar-credit-card-for-spending-with-usdt/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 22:06:38 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/depay-a-virtual-dollar-credit-card-for-spending-with-usdt/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Depay registration and download link: <a href="https://depay.depay.one/web-app/register-h5?invitCode=606096&amp;lang=en-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://depay.depay.one/web-app/register-h5?invitCode=606096&amp;lang=en-us</a>, recommendation code: <strong>606096</strong>.</p>
<p>I found <a href="https://www.v2ex.com/t/912011" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">the topic posted by the boss of Depay on v2ex</a>, the content of this article is mainly based on this topic and my own experience.</p>
<h2 id="what-can-depay-do">What can Depay do?</h2>
<p>Through Depay, you can directly recharge with USDT, convert it into US dollars, and then spend with VISA and mastercard.</p>
<ul>
<li>You can bind Alipay, WeChat Pay, Meituan Takeaway, Pinduoduo, Paypal (China, American, Hong Kong), Tmall International, etc.</li>
<li>Support Stripe merchants, Google Play, Youtube Premium, Paypal merchants, US App Store and e-commerce websites that support non-3DS cards</li>
<li>Support KYC-free card opening to realize completely anonymous payment</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="register-and-download">Register and Download</h2>
<p>Depay registration and download link: <a href="https://depay.depay.one/web-app/register-h5?invitCode=606096&amp;lang=en-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://depay.depay.one/web-app/register-h5?invitCode=606096&amp;lang=en-us</a>, recommendation code: <strong>606096</strong>.</p>
<p>Or use your mobile phone to scan the QR code on the poster below:</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_2121.JPG" title="Depay" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_2121.JPG">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>Android can directly download the APK and install it; iOS can be downloaded in non-Chinese regions App Store, or a beta version can be downloaded.</p>
<h2 id="apply-for-a-virtual-card">Apply for a virtual card</h2>
<p>After entering the Depay App, click Apply for a card. At the beginning, you can choose a standard card and a Lite card. The Lite card does not require KYC. Now there are 5 types of cards (Lite, Standard, Premium, Platinum, Black Gold). The difference is mainly in the card opening fee, monthly fee and recharge fee. The standard card opening fee is 0, the specific difference can be found on the <a href="https://depay.one/en-us/rights.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">official website</a>.</p>
<h2 id="deposit-convert-usd-recharge-and-activate">Deposit, convert USD, recharge and activate</h2>
<p>Depay currently supports charging USDT (TRC20), at least 5 USDT at a time. USDT can be exchanged for USD in real time after deposit. To activate the virtual card, you need to recharge the card with US dollars. There will be a certain percentage of handling fee for the recharging. The handling fee for the standard card is at least 1 US dollar each time, so do not recharge frequently in small amounts.</p>
<p>After activation, you can view the card number and CVV security code.</p>
<h2 id="black-gold-card">Black Gold Card</h2>
<p>At present, as long as you invite 20 people to open a card, you can ask the administrator to upgrade the black gold card. The black gold card has no monthly fee, and the recharge fee is relatively low.</p>
<h2 id="is-depay-safe">Is Depay safe?</h2>
<p>Depay is a newly established small British company. If you are worried, it is best not to charge too much money, just enough.</p>
<h2 id="customer-service">Customer service</h2>
<ul>
<li>Official website: <a href="https://depay.one/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://depay.one/</a></li>
<li>Email: <a href="mailto:support@depay.one" rel="">support@depay.one</a></li>
<li>Telegram group: <a href="https://t.me/depay_visa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://t.me/depay_visa</a></li>
<li>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/Depay_CN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://twitter.com/Depay_CN</a></li>
</ul>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Buy US App Store Gift Cards With Alipay</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/buy-us-app-store-gift-cards-with-alipay/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 10:16:15 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/buy-us-app-store-gift-cards-with-alipay/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Today I learned a way to directly use Alipay to buy US App Store gift cards, so I don’t need to go to Taobao and Xianyu to buy them in the future!</p>
<h2 id="method">method</h2>
<ol>
<li>Open Alipay</li>
<li>Switch to San Francisco in the upper left corner of the home page</li>
<li>Search for &ldquo;出境&rdquo; and select &ldquo;出境&rdquo; in the search results</li>
<li>Select &ldquo;折扣礼卡&rdquo;</li>
<li>Swipe to the bottom of the page and click &ldquo;更多大牌折扣礼卡&rdquo;</li>
<li>Search for &ldquo;App Store&rdquo;</li>
<li>Enter the correct email account</li>
<li>Enter the value you want to buy, at least $2, &ldquo;Purchase card&rdquo;</li>
</ol>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
