<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Journal - Category - kayak4665664</title>
        <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/categories/journal/</link>
        <description>Journal - Category - kayak4665664</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 21:30:53 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kayak4665664.com/categories/journal/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Focus Statistics (Week 03, 2023)</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/focus-statistics-03-2023/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 21:30:53 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/focus-statistics-03-2023/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<br/>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/focus%20statistics/IMG_2097.JPG" title="Focus Statistics (Week 03, 2023)" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/focus%20statistics/IMG_2097.JPG">
        
    </a>
</div>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>First Semester at UCAS</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/first-semester-at-ucas/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 11:00:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/first-semester-at-ucas/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The first semester at UCAS passed quickly, and I feel that the experience of this semester is very rich.</p>
<p>I arrived in Huaibei Town, Huairou District, Beijing on August 17, 2022. I visited Yanqi Lake in the afternoon. Yanqi Lake is a very big lake. There are many trees🌳 by the lake, many boats🛶 on the lake, and many people by the lake. There is also a trail leading to somewhere on the mountain by the lake. I walked on this road for a long time and felt good. Unfortunately, the road was interrupted due to construction🚧. Later, I learned about this road and the viewing platform of UCAS is connected. I saw a lot of birds🐦 on the mountain by the lake. They flew on the lake and chirped on the trees by the lake.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1656.jpeg" title="Yanqi Lake" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1656.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>After staying in a farmhouse inn in the village next to Yanqi Lake for one night, I went to UCAS early the next morning. It rained🌧️ all day, my clothes and shoes were soaked, but when I first arrived at school, everything felt so fresh and I was in a good mood🙂.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1738.jpeg" title="The lotus🪷 pond in the West District of Yanqi Lake Campus of UCAS" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1738.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>With the nucleic acid test every two days, this semester started. The quality and difficulty of the courses offered by UCAS are indeed higher than those offered by NCUT, and I feel that I have gained more. In addition to class, I often ride a bicycle🚲 around the school to see the scenery of the campus. Because the school is backed by mountains and Yanqi Lake, the ecological environment of the school is very good. There are often little animals🐱, and it is said that there are beast of prey such as boars🐗 and snakes🐍.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1901.jpeg" title="Mountains⛰️ in autumn" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1901.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1909.jpeg" title="Hawthorn tree" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1909.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_2026.jpeg" title="Yanqi North Road" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_2026.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>I have to say that UCAS has planted many fruit trees in the mountains. After the autumn harvest, we ate a lot of free fruits.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1872.jpeg" title="Pear🍐" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1872.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>At the end of November, the school became not so peaceful. As the Omicron epidemic became more serious in winter, many colleges and universities in Beijing began to arrange for students to return home. In the beginning, UCAS still required students to complete all the exams at school, and then finally allowed students to return to their hometowns on November 29. All kinds of gossip spread in the school for a while: some people said that there was a student who tested positive for nucleic acid in the school, and all the students could not go home, and they might be quarantined in the dormitory; someone said that after leaving the school and entering the urban area of Beijing, someone would search the mobile phone at the train station or other places&hellip; It feels a bit panicky.</p>
<p>Since the city where my family is located was under lockdown, I didn&rsquo;t know when it would end, so I decided to stay in school. It is said that if there is an epidemic on campus, the cafeteria may not be able to cook normally, so I quickly stocked up some food. At that time, many express delivery services were interrupted, and JD Express also became very slow.</p>
<p>During those few days, most of the students left the school and went home, and the school was quiet. Around December 5, there was a sudden major change in the epidemic prevention policy, and the nucleic acid test every two days was finally ended. But at this time, infected people began to appear in the school, and I also prepared 2 boxes of compound acetaminophen capsules.</p>
<p>After waking up on the morning of December 19th, I felt my throat was dry and a little sore, and there was a lot of nasal discharge. I must have an infection. That night, my sports watch kept warning me my heart🫀 was beating very fast at around 120BMP. I could hear my heart beating while sitting quietly. I was so scared and I lay down on the bed. My whole body was hot, and my heart rate still couldn&rsquo;t drop. With the sound of my heart beating, I finally fell asleep. Checking the records the next morning, the heart rate slowly dropped to around 90BMP, which is very abnormal.</p>
<p>I didn&rsquo;t know what was wrong with this, since it came out in 2019, I didn&rsquo;t know that the new crown virus could affect the heart. I searched on the Internet, and many people have encountered the same situation as me. It is said that it is viral myocarditis. So I quickly placed an order for coenzyme $Q_{10}$ capsules.</p>
<p>On December 22, I went to pick up an antigen detection reagent, and I was indeed infected with the new coronavirus🦠.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_2066.jpeg" title="Antigen test was positive" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_2066.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>After a week, my symptoms gradually disappeared, but I still had some cough and my heart rate was still fast. On December 27, I picked up another antigen test reagent, which was negative this time.</p>
<p>After more than a week, I finished all the exams, my heart rate was still not normal, so I decided to go to Huairou Hospital for a checkup. I did heart color Doppler ultrasound, chest CT scan and multiple blood tests, and the test results showed no abnormalities. The doctor said that my condition should be the sequelae of the new crown rather than myocarditis, and it would take a long time to recover.</p>
<p>It is already 2023, I just hope that we can resume our life before the epidemic as soon as possible🙏.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>I Got My Drivers License🚘</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/i-got-my-driving-license/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 18:56:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/i-got-my-driving-license/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>After more than half a month of training, I successfully got my driving license! Thanks to each of my coaches for their patient guidance!</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1636.JPG" title="driving license" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1636.JPG">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>I also went around the driving school. It&rsquo;s built on a hill and has a wide field of vision.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1586.jpeg" title="Sun🌞" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1586.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>This driving school even has a few ponies.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1581.jpeg" title="Pony🐴" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1581.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1614.jpeg" title="Goose🦢 &amp; Duck🦆" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1614.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>August 18, a New Beginning</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/august-18-a-new-beginning/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 23:43:27 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/august-18-a-new-beginning/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Since the end of the graduation project, I have been looking forward to the letter of admission every day, and it is finally here!</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1547.jpeg" title="letter of admission" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1547.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>Haha, the campus card is here too. I&rsquo;m very much looking forward to the new semester of UCAS, but I have to report on August 18, and I&rsquo;m going to the driving school. I feel that my vacation has ended before it even started🥹</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1544.jpeg" title="degree certificate" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1544.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1546.jpeg" title="graduation certificate" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1546.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>I also received my graduation certificate and degree certificate. I miss those happy days at NCUT.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Next Week I Will Have My Graduation Project Defense</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/next-week-i-will-have-my-graduation-project-defense/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 17:02:51 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/next-week-i-will-have-my-graduation-project-defense/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The graduation project is finally coming to an end, and the final defense will be held on the afternoon of June 9!</p>
<p>Now that I have completed most of the work on my graduation project, these last two weeks have been relatively relax. But I am now quarantined and can only stay in the room every day🙃, and today is the 4th day.</p>
<p>At noon on May 27, I went to the canteen to have lunch as usual. As soon as I returned to my dormitory, I suddenly received a notice from the school asking graduates to leave the school as soon as possible. I realized right away that this would be my last few days at North China University of Technology.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1421.jpeg" title="the notice" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1421.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>I calmed down a bit and immediately started planning what I had to do before I left school. The first thing to consider is my luggage. Fortunately, the school promised that it can be delivered for free. Otherwise, I can&rsquo;t afford the cost of expressing so many things. However, I didn&rsquo;t have a cardboard box for packing. I asked the counselor and he only said it would be released later. I felt his answer was too vague, and I decided to go buy a few cardboard boxes myself. I went to the school express outlet and found the boss there. He told me that our college had taken more than 100 cardboard boxes from him before. I estimated that a student should only get 1 cardboard box. So, I bought 4 large cardboard boxes from the boss for ¥45.</p>
<p>With the cardboard box, I went back to my dormitory to pack the luggage. At the same time, I had to report to the community where my family live. I contacted the staff in the community and she told me that I would be quarantined for 7 days and then quarantined at home for 7 days. I did&rsquo;t think this is reasonable. I have took dozens of nucleic acid tests during school, and they have never been positive, and the school has always been closed. People outside the school can&rsquo;t come in, and people inside the school can&rsquo;t get out. I don&rsquo;t think I should be quarantined for 7 days. And as far as I know, there are some places that do not require centralized quarantine for students returning from Beijing. I explained it to her, but it didn&rsquo;t work. Fortunately, centralized quarantine is free, otherwise it will cost a lot of money. In those days, I saw news that some college students were quarantined after returning home and charged ¥500 a day.</p>
<p>After packing my luggage, I felt a little hot and I noticed that my hair was a little longer. As soon as I thought that I was going to be quarantined for half a month, I went to the barber shop to cut my hair short.</p>
<p>In the evening, the counselor finally informed us that we could go get the cardboard box, and I got a cardboard box and a sack. With the 4 large cardboard boxes I bought, it was just right.</p>
<p>On the morning of May 28, I went to the supermarket to buy a marker and I had to mark my address on the box. I walked into the dormitory building, and a dormitory administrator who was familiar with me told me that I could take my luggage to the express outlet now, and reminded me to hurry up. Considering that I have to move 4 cartons and 1 sack from the dormitory to the outlet, it is not easy to rely on only two hands, so I went to the outlet and borrowed a flatbed trolley from the boss. I went back to my dormitory, marked all 5 items with my information, put them all on the trolley, and all of them were shipped to the express outlet at once.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1332.jpeg" title="the flatbed trolley" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1332.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>Since the notice of the graduates leaving the school was rushed, the boss of the express outlet frankly said that they did not know how to handle the luggage of so many students, and there were only two people in the entire outlet including him. When I pushed the flat trolley to the outlet, I saw that there were already many boxes piled up outside. I was a little worried that so many boxes would be confused, so I asked the boss to affix notes to my luggage first, so that I could also track it easily. By the time I had dealt with all this, it was already past 12 o&rsquo;clock. When I arrived at the canteen, I bought a large plate of Jiaozi. I have to say that it is really delicious, with a lot of meat in it.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1333.jpeg" title="Jiaozi" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1333.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>At night, I tracked that my luggage had been sent out, and I felt that they were really efficient.</p>
<p>On the afternoon of May 29, the boss suddenly called me. What I was worried about had happened. He said that they made the wrong notes and sent a box of other people&rsquo;s luggage to my address, and my box is still in the outlet😱. I hurried to the outlet again, and one of my boxes was still lying on the shelf.</p>
<p>On May 30, there is nothing special on this day, everything has been dealt with.</p>
<p>On May 31, I woke up before the alarm went off, my last day at school. Get up for breakfast. After that, I started packing sheets, quilts, pillows and my suitcase. I had to bring enough daily necessities, and I was going to be quarantined at night. I packed the bedding into the little cardboard box released by the college, and it just fit inside. I took the box to the outlet, the door was open but no one was there. After waiting for half an hour, the boss finally came.</p>
<p>At noon, I went to the canteen for lunch, which was my last meal at school.</p>
<p>I went back to my dormitory and lay on the mattress. This mattress is too big to be expressed, so I left it here.</p>
<p>At about 3pm, I packed my suitcase, closed the windows, turned off the electric breaker switch, took a last look at my dormitory, and locked the door. I went downstairs to the dormitory administrator and returned my key.</p>
<p>And then I left school and probably never went back.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1377.JPG" title="NCUT" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1377.JPG">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>The photo above was taken on the 31st. On the afternoon of the 30th, I saw someone playing with these signs, but it was still 2021 at that time.</p>
<p>After leaving school, I took the subway to the train station.</p>
<p>At about 8pm, I got off the train. Soon, someone started to check the traveler&rsquo;s place of departure. I was leaving from Beijing and needed to be sent to a quarantine hotel.</p>
<p>After I filled out a document, my ID was seized. They said they would give it back to me. I don&rsquo;t know who they are, but I think their behavior violates the Resident Identity Card Law of the People&rsquo;s Republic of China. After that, there was a long wait, standing for more than 2 hours, and no one came to deal with it. Overall, it was an unpleasant experience.</p>
<p>At about 10pm, someone finally came to meet us, and finally returned my ID card to me. Then we took nucleic acid tests.</p>
<p>Our group got into the car and finally arrived at the quarantine hotel around 11pm. Another long wait, I was already sleepy and exhausted. After another nucleic acid test, I finally entered the room. After the bed was made, it was nearly 1:00 on June 1st.</p>
<p>To be honest, the environment of the hotel is not bad, I can eat and drink on time, and I have had a good time in the past 4 days.</p>
<p>There are still 3 days of centralized quarantine that will end, and 7 days of home quarantine will begin. During this period, the final defense will be held on June 9.</p>
<p>Time flies so fast. When I went back to school on March 15, it was still snowing in Beijing. In a blink of an eye, I suddenly went home again. My 4 years of university life are coming to an end soon, and I will always remember the 4 years at North China University of Technology.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Celebrating International Workers&#39; Day</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/international-workers-day/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 21:34:29 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/international-workers-day/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Workers of the world, unite!</p>
<p>Work together to defend our rights and fight for a fairer and better world.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Today&#39;s Thesis Proposal</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/todays-thesis-proposal/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 20:57:08 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/todays-thesis-proposal/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Today I participated in the thesis proposal through the Tencent Meeting.</p>
<p>The original plan was to start at 1:30 p.m. I don&rsquo;t know why we waited until 2 p.m😶. There were 24 students and 3 judges in this thesis proposal this afternoon. I was number 12 and waited until 4 p.m to finally get my turn. Overall, it went relatively smoothly, but there was a teacher who was studying computer network coincidentally, and my topic involved a lot of network stuff, so I was questioned closely.</p>
<p>After my turn, because the teacher didn&rsquo;t say we could withdraw, I just continued to stay in the meeting to watch others. An unnamed student who was recommended to study at the Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences for postgraduate study without examination, his graduation project was in cooperation with Huawei. He said that the results of his graduation project would beat the previous work of his supervisor, and he was determined to submit a paper to the top conference as well👍.</p>
<p>Such excellent classmates inspire me to do my own work better, keep working hard👍.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Made a Cake Again🍰</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/made-a-cake-again/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 22:42:11 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/made-a-cake-again/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The flour may be less, it&rsquo;s not as good as last time. Not bad.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1024.jpeg" title="cake" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1024.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Pingyao Ancient City</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/pingyao-ancient-city/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 22:30:26 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/pingyao-ancient-city/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I went to Pingyao Ancient City. The entire ancient city basically preserves the original appearance of the Ming and Qing Dynasties. It&rsquo;s very spectacular to gaze into the distance from the city wall. There are many snacks, my favorite is Pingyao beef and wantuo!</p>
<p>I didn&rsquo;t take any good-looking photos, and here are two I took on the southern city wall.</p>
<div align="center">
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0986.jpeg" title="the south gate" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0986.jpeg" data-sub-html="<h2>the south gate</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">the south gate</figcaption>
    </figure>
</div>
<div align="center">
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0988.jpeg" title="hongyi cannons" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0988.jpeg" data-sub-html="<h2>hongyi cannons</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">hongyi cannons</figcaption>
    </figure>
</div>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Made a Cake🍰</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/made-a-cake/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 22:00:24 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/made-a-cake/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Yummy!</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0917.jpeg" title="  ke" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0917.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0919.jpeg" title="cake" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_0919.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
