<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>My Website - Tag - kayak4665664</title>
        <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/my-website/</link>
        <description>My Website - Tag - kayak4665664</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 17:17:30 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/my-website/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>How My Wesite Was Built?</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/how-my-wesite-was-built/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 17:17:30 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/how-my-wesite-was-built/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>At present, my website has stabilized and entered the routine maintenance stage. Now let&rsquo;s review how it was built. There are various guidelines on the Internet, and this article is mainly about my own experience, so I won&rsquo;t involve those repeated details.</p>
<h2 id="beginning">Beginning</h2>
<p>Two weeks ago, I saw someone using Github as a free cloud drive. I have seen someone take notes and blog in a repository. Suddenly, I wanted to have a place to write something to record myself. I searched for how to blog on Github, and then I found <a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Github Pages</a>. In short, it can automatically host static webpages for free, and it is more than enough to build a blog of my own.</p>
<h3 id="domain">Domain</h3>
<p><a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Github Pages</a> is free, but its URLs all look like <code>username.github.io</code>, which feels not personalized enough. Fortunately, it supports custom domains, so I decided to buy one. The website hadn&rsquo;t been built yet, but I bought it first. I heard that buying a domain in China requires real-name verification, and the verification takes several days. If I wait for the verification while building my website, it will save time. Finally, I bought <code>kayak4665664.com</code>.</p>
<div class="details admonition tip open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-lightbulb fa-fw"></i>Tip<i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content">Some domains look cheap when they are registered in the first year, but later renewals are more expensive than <code>.com</code> domain.</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<h3 id="usernamegithubio">username.github.io</h3>
<p>Created a new repository and set <code>Pages</code> settings. <a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Github Pages</a> uses <code>Jekyll</code> to transform plain text into static websites, so it will let you choose your <code>Jekyll</code> theme during the setup process. I even carefully compared those themes and chose the one that I thought was the best-looking. In fact, I soon discovered that these themes were too simple to meet my needs. Then I used <code>git</code> to clone the repository to the local.</p>
<h3 id="design">Design</h3>
<p>I visited some others&rsquo; websites and initially determined that my website should have the functions of comments, visit count, and in-site search. In addition, I also wanted to add Baidu and Google Analytics, and let them index my website.</p>
<h3 id="tool">Tool</h3>
<p>In addition to <code>Jekyll</code>, there are many tools for transforming plain text into static websites and blogs, such as the <code>Hugo</code> I use now. Since <a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Github Pages</a> uses <code>Jekyll</code> by default, I chose <code>Jekyll</code>.</p>
<p><code>Jekyll</code> is based on <code>Ruby</code> and can be installed with <code>gem</code>. I use macOS and <code>Ruby</code> is a built-in software. I directly executed <code>gem install jekyll bundler</code> to start installing <code>Jekyll</code>, <code>Bundler</code> and their dependencies. During the installation, <code>fatal error:'ruby/config.h' file not found</code> appeared. I googled it and found that some people said the version of the built-in <code>Ruby</code> was too low, but others said that it was a problem with <code>Xcode CommandLineTools</code>. I installed a new <code>Ruby</code> with <code>Homebrew</code> directly. After installation, set the environment variables in terminal, re-executed <code>gem install jekyll bundler</code>, and the installation was complete this time.</p>
<div class="details admonition warning open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-exclamation-triangle fa-fw"></i>Warning<i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content">I also searched for how to clean up the cache and installed packages of the last <code>gem install jekyll bundler</code>, but I didn&rsquo;t find it. I had to manually uninstall the installed packages and delete the directory where the cache was located. I felt that it was not cleaned up at all.</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<h2 id="jekyll">Jekyll</h2>
<h3 id="getting-start">Getting start</h3>
<p>Executed <code>bundle exec jekyll serve</code> in the workplace, and <code>cannot load such file - webrick (LoadError)</code> appeared. I googled it and then solved it with <code>bundle add webrick</code>.</p>
<p>I previewed it locally and felt there were no problems. I prepared to <code>push</code> it to Github and test it with my mobile phone. But there was a problem, <code>push</code> did not work. Google didn&rsquo;t find it, but Baidu found that it may be a problem with <code>proxy</code>. It was resolved after unseting the proxy settings of <code>git</code>.</p>
<p>Browsing with my phone, the webpage was automatically adapted to the mobile interface. At this time, I found that this theme was too simple, and it didn&rsquo;t even have a pagination. At the beginning, I was planning to implement it myself, but I thought that so many functions would have to be implemented one by one, and the workload was huge. I&rsquo;d better find a theme with more complete functions.</p>
<h3 id="theme">Theme</h3>
<p>There are many <code>Jekyll</code> themes on the Internet, and finally downloaded <a href="https://github.com/jeffreytse/jekyll-theme-yat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">YAT</a>. It has many functions. We can use <a href="Disqus.com" rel="">Disqus</a> and <a href="https://github.com/imsun/gitment" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Gitment</a> to comment.</p>
<p>After downloading, I wanted to execute <code>bundle exec jekyll serve</code> to preview it, the error <code>Could not find gem 'jekyll-spaceship (~&gt; 0.2)'</code> appeared. I solved it by setting the version to <code>0.2</code> when installing <code>jekyll-spaceship</code> by <code>gem</code>. Here I also found that the installation was stuck, but there was no error. Using the <code>Activity Monitor</code>, I saw that the <code>Rcvd Bytes</code> of <code>Ruby</code> has been increasing slowly, which should be a network problem in China. Googled it, then found a way on <a href="https://gems.ruby-china.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Ruby China</a> to change the sources. The installation was successful after changing them.</p>
<p>Executed <code>bundle exec jekyll serve</code> again and this time I previewed the new theme.</p>
<h3 id="personalizing">Personalizing</h3>
<p>According to our own needs, we can make personalized changes to the theme, such as titles, pictures, etc. I originally wanted to use <a href="https://github.com/imsun/gitment" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Gitment</a>, but I found that it can&rsquo;t log in to the Github account. I took a look at its <a href="https://github.com/imsun/gitment/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Issues</a> then found that the service should be stopped. So I can only use <a href="Disqus.com" rel="">Disqus</a>, I registered <a href="Disqus.com" rel="">Disqus</a> account and turned on the comment function. In addition, I also used <a href="http://busuanzi.ibruce.info" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Bu Suanzi</a> for website traffic statistics, which only requires two lines of code.</p>
<p>Then I started to add some content. In the process of previewing the content, I gradually discovered some problems. The font of this theme was too small, and the contrast between the text and the background was low whether in light or dark mode. In short, I felt that reading it tortures my eyes. However, the font cannot be set in the configuration file. I can only modified the <code>.scss</code> files one by one, which is more troublesome. And its translation function called Google&rsquo;s webpage translation interface, which was almost unusable under the Chinese network, causing the webpage to become stuck. I directly deleted the translation-related part of the source code. In addition, <a href="Disqus.com" rel="">Disqus</a> cannot log in to the account under the Chinese network. After a test, only anonymous guest comments can be used. This is also a disadvantage.</p>
<h3 id="giving-up">Giving up</h3>
<p>After personalization, I felt that there was no problem. It suddenly occurred to me that the <a href="https://github.com/jeffreytse/jekyll-theme-yat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">YAT</a> theme also supports PlantUML, Mermaid, Mathjax, Vedio, Audio, etc. I should test it again. I directly used the author&rsquo;s <code>markdown</code> files to test and found that these things were not displayed normally.</p>
<p>I thought it was because I changed the source code. I directly cloned the author&rsquo;s repository. After testing, I found that the same does not work. It seems that it is not a problem with my code modification. But I haven&rsquo;t found the problem. Considering that there were other shortcomings in this theme, I chose to abandon it.</p>
<p>I started looking for the subject again, this time more carefully. Finally, I found the <a href="https://github.com/dillonzq/LoveIt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">LoveIt</a> theme, which is what I use now.</p>
<p>This is a theme based on <code>Hugo</code>, so <code>Ruby</code> was useless, I uninstalled it.</p>
<h2 id="hugo">Hugo</h2>
<h3 id="getting-start-1">Getting start</h3>
<p>First used <code>Homebrew</code> to install <code>Hugo</code>, <a href="https://github.com/dillonzq/LoveIt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">LoveIt</a> recommends installing the <code>extended</code> version of <code>Hugo</code>, and the <code>Hugo</code> installed by <code>Homebrew</code> is the <code>extended</code> version.</p>
<p>The directory structure of <code>Hugo</code> is still different from that of <code>Jekyll</code>, it took some time to get familiar. <a href="https://github.com/dillonzq/LoveIt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">LoveIt</a> has a lot of configuration items, and we need to take a look at the document first.</p>
<p>Approximately configured, executed <code>hugo serve -e production --disableFastRender</code> to preview.</p>
<h3 id="personalizing-1">Personalizing</h3>
<p>After that was personalized settings, as well as:</p>
<ol>
<li>Registered <a href="https://www.leancloud.cn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">LeanCloud</a> and <a href="https://valine.js.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Valine</a> for comments and visit statistics</li>
<li>Used <a href="https://realfavicongenerator.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://realfavicongenerator.net</a> to generate website icons</li>
<li>Registered <a href="http://Gravatar.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Gravartar</a></li>
<li>Registered <a href="https://www.algolia.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Algolia</a> for site search</li>
<li>Used <code>node.js</code> to execute <code>npm install atomic-algolia</code> to install <a href="https://github.com/chrisdmacrae/atomic-algolia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">atomic-algolia</a> to automatically upload index files to <a href="https://www.algolia.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Algolia</a></li>
<li>Registered <a href="https://www.mapbox.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Mapbox</a></li>
</ol>
<p>During this period, I also found a problem. The custom <code>404</code> template could not be displayed in the local preview. Google found it:
<div class="details admonition info open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-info-circle fa-fw"></i>Info<i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content"><code>hugo server</code> will not automatically load your custom <code>404.html</code> file, but you can test the appearance of your custom “not found” page by navigating your browser to <code>/404.html</code>.</div>
        </div>
    </div></p>
<h3 id="extension">Extension</h3>
<p>The website was almost built. Executed <code>hugo</code>, and the <code>/public</code> directory would appear. Synchronized <code>/public</code> with our own repository, and we can host the webpage to <a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Github Pages</a>. Then used <a href="https://github.com/chrisdmacrae/atomic-algolia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">atomic-algolia</a> to upload the generated index file to <a href="https://www.algolia.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Algolia</a>. After these two steps, a website deployment was completed.</p>
<p>In addition, I built a private repository for synchronizing source code other than <code>/public</code>, so every deployment needs to be synchronized once more. In order to automate these three processes, I wrote a <code>Shell</code> script. Only one step.</p>
<p>At this time, my domain finally passed the real-name verification. I started to make some extensions:</p>
<ol>
<li>Set up <code>CNAME</code> on Github</li>
<li>Imported the repository into <a href="https://vercel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Vercel</a>, so that every time the repository is updated, it will be automatically deployed to <a href="https://vercel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Vercel</a>. It is said that Baidu will not index sites hosted by <a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Github Pages</a>, and it can be indexed after being deployed to <a href="https://vercel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Vercel</a></li>
<li>Set a custom domain in <a href="https://vercel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Vercel</a></li>
<li>Added <a href="https://tongji.baidu.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Baidu Tongji</a> and <a href="https://analytics.google.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Google Analytics</a></li>
<li>Submitted the <code>sitemap</code> to <a href="https://ziyuan.baidu.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Baidu Ziyuan</a> and <a href="https://search.google.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Google Search Console</a>, in <a href="https://www.bing.com/webmasters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Bing Webmaster Tools</a> directly imported the submitted <code>sitemap</code> in <a href="https://search.google.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Google Search Console</a></li>
</ol>
<h2 id="end">End</h2>
<p>In the future, I also plan to add a little Google advertisement, which is also a feature of most websites.</p>
<p>In general, there are a lot of gains this time!</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Google Has Indexed My Website</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/google-has-indexed-my-website/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:23:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/google-has-indexed-my-website/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Google has indexed my website! At present, I have also submitted the <code>sitemap</code> to Baidu and Bing, waiting to be indexed.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/3kRSMBH98fmr1y6.png" title="Google" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/3kRSMBH98fmr1y6.png">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>Now my website is gradually getting on track, so I am going to write an article next week to review how my website was built.</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
