<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>graduation project - Tag - kayak4665664</title>
        <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/graduation-project/</link>
        <description>graduation project - Tag - kayak4665664</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>contact@kayak4665664.com (kayak4665664)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 17:02:51 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kayak4665664.com/tags/graduation-project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Next Week I Will Have My Graduation Project Defense</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/next-week-i-will-have-my-graduation-project-defense/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 17:02:51 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/next-week-i-will-have-my-graduation-project-defense/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The graduation project is finally coming to an end, and the final defense will be held on the afternoon of June 9!</p>
<p>Now that I have completed most of the work on my graduation project, these last two weeks have been relatively relax. But I am now quarantined and can only stay in the room every day🙃, and today is the 4th day.</p>
<p>At noon on May 27, I went to the canteen to have lunch as usual. As soon as I returned to my dormitory, I suddenly received a notice from the school asking graduates to leave the school as soon as possible. I realized right away that this would be my last few days at North China University of Technology.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1421.jpeg" title="the notice" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1421.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>I calmed down a bit and immediately started planning what I had to do before I left school. The first thing to consider is my luggage. Fortunately, the school promised that it can be delivered for free. Otherwise, I can&rsquo;t afford the cost of expressing so many things. However, I didn&rsquo;t have a cardboard box for packing. I asked the counselor and he only said it would be released later. I felt his answer was too vague, and I decided to go buy a few cardboard boxes myself. I went to the school express outlet and found the boss there. He told me that our college had taken more than 100 cardboard boxes from him before. I estimated that a student should only get 1 cardboard box. So, I bought 4 large cardboard boxes from the boss for ¥45.</p>
<p>With the cardboard box, I went back to my dormitory to pack the luggage. At the same time, I had to report to the community where my family live. I contacted the staff in the community and she told me that I would be quarantined for 7 days and then quarantined at home for 7 days. I did&rsquo;t think this is reasonable. I have took dozens of nucleic acid tests during school, and they have never been positive, and the school has always been closed. People outside the school can&rsquo;t come in, and people inside the school can&rsquo;t get out. I don&rsquo;t think I should be quarantined for 7 days. And as far as I know, there are some places that do not require centralized quarantine for students returning from Beijing. I explained it to her, but it didn&rsquo;t work. Fortunately, centralized quarantine is free, otherwise it will cost a lot of money. In those days, I saw news that some college students were quarantined after returning home and charged ¥500 a day.</p>
<p>After packing my luggage, I felt a little hot and I noticed that my hair was a little longer. As soon as I thought that I was going to be quarantined for half a month, I went to the barber shop to cut my hair short.</p>
<p>In the evening, the counselor finally informed us that we could go get the cardboard box, and I got a cardboard box and a sack. With the 4 large cardboard boxes I bought, it was just right.</p>
<p>On the morning of May 28, I went to the supermarket to buy a marker and I had to mark my address on the box. I walked into the dormitory building, and a dormitory administrator who was familiar with me told me that I could take my luggage to the express outlet now, and reminded me to hurry up. Considering that I have to move 4 cartons and 1 sack from the dormitory to the outlet, it is not easy to rely on only two hands, so I went to the outlet and borrowed a flatbed trolley from the boss. I went back to my dormitory, marked all 5 items with my information, put them all on the trolley, and all of them were shipped to the express outlet at once.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1332.jpeg" title="the flatbed trolley" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1332.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>Since the notice of the graduates leaving the school was rushed, the boss of the express outlet frankly said that they did not know how to handle the luggage of so many students, and there were only two people in the entire outlet including him. When I pushed the flat trolley to the outlet, I saw that there were already many boxes piled up outside. I was a little worried that so many boxes would be confused, so I asked the boss to affix notes to my luggage first, so that I could also track it easily. By the time I had dealt with all this, it was already past 12 o&rsquo;clock. When I arrived at the canteen, I bought a large plate of Jiaozi. I have to say that it is really delicious, with a lot of meat in it.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1333.jpeg" title="Jiaozi" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1333.jpeg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>At night, I tracked that my luggage had been sent out, and I felt that they were really efficient.</p>
<p>On the afternoon of May 29, the boss suddenly called me. What I was worried about had happened. He said that they made the wrong notes and sent a box of other people&rsquo;s luggage to my address, and my box is still in the outlet😱. I hurried to the outlet again, and one of my boxes was still lying on the shelf.</p>
<p>On May 30, there is nothing special on this day, everything has been dealt with.</p>
<p>On May 31, I woke up before the alarm went off, my last day at school. Get up for breakfast. After that, I started packing sheets, quilts, pillows and my suitcase. I had to bring enough daily necessities, and I was going to be quarantined at night. I packed the bedding into the little cardboard box released by the college, and it just fit inside. I took the box to the outlet, the door was open but no one was there. After waiting for half an hour, the boss finally came.</p>
<p>At noon, I went to the canteen for lunch, which was my last meal at school.</p>
<p>I went back to my dormitory and lay on the mattress. This mattress is too big to be expressed, so I left it here.</p>
<p>At about 3pm, I packed my suitcase, closed the windows, turned off the electric breaker switch, took a last look at my dormitory, and locked the door. I went downstairs to the dormitory administrator and returned my key.</p>
<p>And then I left school and probably never went back.</p>
<div align="center">
<a class="lightgallery" href="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1377.JPG" title="NCUT" data-thumbnail="https://cdn.kayak4665664.com/IMG_1377.JPG">
        
    </a>
</div>
<p>The photo above was taken on the 31st. On the afternoon of the 30th, I saw someone playing with these signs, but it was still 2021 at that time.</p>
<p>After leaving school, I took the subway to the train station.</p>
<p>At about 8pm, I got off the train. Soon, someone started to check the traveler&rsquo;s place of departure. I was leaving from Beijing and needed to be sent to a quarantine hotel.</p>
<p>After I filled out a document, my ID was seized. They said they would give it back to me. I don&rsquo;t know who they are, but I think their behavior violates the Resident Identity Card Law of the People&rsquo;s Republic of China. After that, there was a long wait, standing for more than 2 hours, and no one came to deal with it. Overall, it was an unpleasant experience.</p>
<p>At about 10pm, someone finally came to meet us, and finally returned my ID card to me. Then we took nucleic acid tests.</p>
<p>Our group got into the car and finally arrived at the quarantine hotel around 11pm. Another long wait, I was already sleepy and exhausted. After another nucleic acid test, I finally entered the room. After the bed was made, it was nearly 1:00 on June 1st.</p>
<p>To be honest, the environment of the hotel is not bad, I can eat and drink on time, and I have had a good time in the past 4 days.</p>
<p>There are still 3 days of centralized quarantine that will end, and 7 days of home quarantine will begin. During this period, the final defense will be held on June 9.</p>
<p>Time flies so fast. When I went back to school on March 15, it was still snowing in Beijing. In a blink of an eye, I suddenly went home again. My 4 years of university life are coming to an end soon, and I will always remember the 4 years at North China University of Technology.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Today&#39;s Thesis Proposal</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/todays-thesis-proposal/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 20:57:08 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/todays-thesis-proposal/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Today I participated in the thesis proposal through the Tencent Meeting.</p>
<p>The original plan was to start at 1:30 p.m. I don&rsquo;t know why we waited until 2 p.m😶. There were 24 students and 3 judges in this thesis proposal this afternoon. I was number 12 and waited until 4 p.m to finally get my turn. Overall, it went relatively smoothly, but there was a teacher who was studying computer network coincidentally, and my topic involved a lot of network stuff, so I was questioned closely.</p>
<p>After my turn, because the teacher didn&rsquo;t say we could withdraw, I just continued to stay in the meeting to watch others. An unnamed student who was recommended to study at the Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences for postgraduate study without examination, his graduation project was in cooperation with Huawei. He said that the results of his graduation project would beat the previous work of his supervisor, and he was determined to submit a paper to the top conference as well👍.</p>
<p>Such excellent classmates inspire me to do my own work better, keep working hard👍.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Graduation Project Starts Now</title>
    <link>https://www.kayak4665664.com/graduation-project-starts-now/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 20:32:09 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.kayak4665664.com/graduation-project-starts-now/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This week my school started the work of the graduation project, and now I have determined the topic and officially started my graduation project.</p>
<h2 id="topic-selection">Topic selection</h2>
<p>I already selected a topic before, which was proposed to me by my master tutor. It&rsquo;s about cyber security. I think it&rsquo;s quite appropriate. On the one hand, I can learn some knowledge about cyber security in advance, on the other hand, I can also complete my graduation project. This is killing two birds with one stone.</p>
<h2 id="meeting">Meeting</h2>
<p>After the mobilization meeting of the graduation project, I met with my adviser. He hosted a short meeting for us and talked a lot. It’s nothing. The only thing is that a WeCom group was created, and he became the &ldquo;寨主 (zhàizhǔ, brigand chief)&rdquo;.</p>
<h2 id="report">Report</h2>
<p>Although I selected a topic before, I still need to think about it seriously. After all, the graduation project is not so casual. My adviser posted some reference topics in the group, all of which are quite classic. However, that topic is very new to me. I have never worked in this field before. In general, I prefer the topic of cyber security, and my master tutor also hopes that I will complete this topic very well. So I reported it to my adviser.</p>
<h2 id="discussion">Discussion</h2>
<div class="details admonition quote open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-quote-right fa-fw"></i>What the adviser said: <i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content"><p>The 题目 (tímù, It means &ldquo;title&rdquo; or &ldquo;topic&rdquo; in Chinese.) is incomplete.</p>
<p>Write a complete one.</p>
</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<p>Okay, I described my topic more completely, waiting for his opinion. The message has been read, but there has been no reply. It&rsquo;s inexplicable, wouldn&rsquo;t he forget it? The next day, I sent him a message and asked his opinion again, and suddenly received a 59 second voice message.</p>
<div class="details admonition quote open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-quote-right fa-fw"></i>What the adviser said: <i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content">&hellip; Yous is not a 题目 at all, yours is just a spoken expression. How could that be a 题目? And the work you will do, to be honest, is too searchable. I can’t say&hellip; If I don’t see the specific content. Then what you do can be more or less. The requirements for you, I don’t know&hellip; If it’s low, it’s very simple and not too difficult; if it&rsquo;s high, that&rsquo;s a certain degree of difficulty, okay? Then you wrote so much, how could yours be a 题目? Yours is Just a Spoken Expression! Your spoken expression, how can I decide for you? You want to determine it, can I decide a spoken expression for you? Can it be a 题目? You can&rsquo;t write a 题目 yourself, you ask me to decide? Deciding a spoken expression for you, is appropriate? Ok? After you’ve thought about it yourself, we will have a basis for discussion. Otherwise, there is nothing to say!</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<p>I was stunned, he said mine is not a topic. Regardless of whether it is a topic or not, if he thinks mine is not a topic and he has opinions or questions, couldn&rsquo;t he tell me directly? I can modify or improve it! He keeps not replying, can I know what he thinks?</p>
<p>I experienced this situation for the first time since I was born, and I didn&rsquo;t know what it meant to me. I also told my master tutor about this matter.</p>
<div class="details admonition quote open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-quote-right fa-fw"></i>The first message she replied to was: <i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content">Why?</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<p>I also showed her the voice of my adviser, and she helped me determine a title. Here I suddenly discovered that there may be a misunderstanding. Does the &ldquo;题目&rdquo; mentioned by my adviser refer to the &ldquo;title&rdquo; or the &ldquo;topic&rdquo;? I checked the <em>Modern Chinese Normative Dictionary</em>, &ldquo;题目&rdquo; does have multiple meanings. He said that my &ldquo;题目&rdquo; was a &ldquo;spoken expression&rdquo;, and it seemed that the &ldquo;题目&rdquo; mentioned by him refers to the &ldquo;title&rdquo;.</p>
<p>If so, why didn&rsquo;t he make it clear at the beginning that he was talking about a title?</p>
<p>Well, he said that I can&rsquo;t write a title myself, and there is no basis for discussion. Then I sent him the determined title, hoping for further discussion. However, he still has nothing to say.</p>
<p>At that time, I felt that the &ldquo;title&rdquo; or &ldquo;topic&rdquo; may not be the key. I thought of him saying in the group, &ldquo;from this class, the educational administration is going to start the graduation project management system&rdquo;, &ldquo;all through the system&rdquo;, &ldquo;leave traces&rdquo;. &ldquo;Moreover&rdquo;, &ldquo;qualification for the Washington Accord is in progress&rdquo;, &ldquo;advisers strictly control the quality of topics&rdquo;. I thought it may not be easy for him to check the professional level and workload of this topic. After all, he is not researching cyber security, and there should be no similar topics in the past. He has been difficult to conclude, so he has nothing to say.</p>
<p>I told my master tutor what I thought, and she suggested that I explain it to him in more detail. Therefore, I wrote a document that was a bit like an opening report. I wrote out the specific tasks to be done, and also initially planned the time allocation for each task. I sent it to my adviser and asked him to express his opinions directly if he had any questions.</p>
<p>Finally, my adviser started to discuss it with me.</p>
<div class="details admonition quote open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-quote-right fa-fw"></i>What the adviser said: <i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content">You can submit it.</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<h2 id="end">End</h2>
<p>In any case, the topic has been determined, and now it&rsquo;s time to complete the project.</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
